Register of the Ethiopian Subject Collection, 1962-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
Ethiopian Subject Collection,
1962-2001
XX781
5 manuscript boxes, 1 phonorecord, 2 phonotape cassettes (2.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, reports, press releases, communiqués, newsletters, conference papers, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to social, political and economic conditions in Ethiopia, and to drought and famine, revolutionary movements, and post-1974 military conflicts in Ethiopia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Ethiopia--History--1974-; Droughts--Ethiopia.; Ethiopia--Famines.; Ethiopia.; Africa.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1962-1994 (Box 1)
  Brochure, correspondence, flyer, newsletter, printed matter, profile, record of proceedings, report, statment and survey relating to civil rights, foreign relations, social, political and military conditions in Ethiopia
- DROUGHT AND FAMINE, 1973-1994 (Box 1)
  Articles, brochure, clippings, flyers, newsletters and printed matter relating to famine and relief activities in Ethiopia
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1979-1994 (Box 2)
  Brochure, newsletter, news release and printed matter relating to revolutionary movements in Ethiopia
- INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT GROUPS, 1981-1994 (Box 2)
  Newsletter, printed matter and report relating to the role of the support groups in response to the human rights violations and democratic movements in Ethiopia
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1985 (Record cabinet)
  Phonorecord, "Tam Tam Pour L'Ethiopie"
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after December 1994.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1962-1994
  - General (Box 1)
  - Ethiopian Democratic Union (EDU)
  - Ethiopians in Michigan
  - Ethiopian Student Union in North America
  - Foreign relations
    - Soviet Union
    - United Nations
  - Health
  - Jews
    - General
    - American Association for Ethiopian Jews
  - Paris Conference on Peace in Ethiopia, 1993 March 11
  - Politics and government
    - General
    - Transitional Period Charter of Ethiopia
    - Tigray
  - Sudan
- DROUGHT AND FAMINE, 1973-1994
  - General (Box 1)
    - 1973-1975
    - 1983-1986
    - 1988
  - Ethiopian Famine Relief Organization
  - Relief and Rehabilitation Commission
  - Relief Society of Tigray
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1979-1994
  - General (Box 2)
  - All Amhara Peoples Organization (AAPO)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science Human Rights Action Network (AAASHRAN)
  - Coalition of Ethiopian Democratic Forces (COEDF)
  - Ethiopian Peoples Revolutionary Party
  - Ethiopian People's Revolutionary Democratic Front (EPRDF)
  - Oromo Liberation Front
  - Tigray People's Liberation Front (TPLF)
- INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT GROUPS, 1981-1994
  - Amnesty International (Box 2)
  - Ethiopian Association in Mid-West America (EAMWA)
  - League of Red Cross
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1985
  - Phonorecord. "Tam Tam Pour L'Ethiopie" (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 3-5, Phonotape cassettes:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described